CHRISTINA LOIACONO

loiaconochristina@gmail.com | (646) 678-1992 GitHub Profile | LinkedIn Profile

SKILLS

Front End: JavaScript ES6, Git, GitHub, React, Redux, HTML, CSS, Python

Back End: Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, API Creation/ Implementation, Heroku, Firebase

Design Software: Adobe CC: Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign. NedGraphics: prints, wovens/knits. Pointcarré

PROJECTS

CryptoTalk App - PERN Stack (PostgreSQL, Express, React, Node), JavaScript

This web application provides educational resources about cryptocurrencies and uses the PERN stack with full CRUD.

- Worked collaboratively in a team, utilizing GitHub to maintain code on multiple branches during development.
- Planned the entire app and additional features from start to finish, and deployed the app using Netlify and Heroku.
- Built and integrated a one-to-many table relationship in the backend, to be used on the frontend.

CTA Store App - PERN Stack (PostgreSQL, Express, React, Node), JavaScript

This project was to build an e-commerce web application using the PERN stack with full CRUD operations.

- Used Express and Postgres to build the backend. Used React to build the frontend.
- Allows a user to create, read, update, and delete products. Additional feature: shopping cart.
- Deployed the app using Netlify and Heroku.

Budgeting App - PERN Stack (PostgreSQL, Express, React, Node), JavaScript

This budgeting application utilizes the PERN stack with full CRUD. The frontend is a React app using RESTful routes.

- Allows a user to create, read, update and delete transactions.
- Used helper functions to change the color of transactions to show if the amount is above \$1,000 or below \$0.
- Additional feature: adding the bank account total to the navbar so the user can always see how much money they have.

EXPERIENCE

HOME TEXTILE DESIGNER - Freelance (New York, NY)

Nov. 2020 - Jun. 2021

- Projects for clients included: Shower curtains, storage bins, and packaging design.
- Fully efficient in mid/senior-level design work using Adobe CC Photoshop and Illustrator.

CREATIVE BATH PRODUCTS, INC. - DESIGN ASSISTANT (New York, NY)

Nov. 2018 - Mar. 2020

- Took artwork to final production-ready layouts. Strong technical skills in repeats, layouts.
- Excellent color sense, managed many projects in a timely manner. NedGraphics, Photoshop, Illustrator.

SKY HOME USA; GUL AHMED TEXTILE MILLS LTD. - Associate Designer (NYC)

Mar. 2017 - Oct. 2018; Oct. 2015 - Oct. 2018

- Created and developed brands for the showroom. Designed packaging, merchandised products.
- Communicated with clients and factories daily, designed soft home products, created specs.
- Approved designs, Pantone colors, trends; tested factory capabilities and manufacturing processes.

EDUCATION

Pursuit | Full Stack Web Fellow

2021 - Present

Intensive 12-month software engineering fellowship with a 9% acceptance rate.

Fashion Institute of Technology, SUNY | Bachelor of Fine Arts (BFA) Degree, Textile/Surface Design

2012-2014

Minor: Art History